<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>CS371p Spring 2016: Tipparat Umrod</title>
    <description>Computer Science | Computational Biology Class of 2016 | University of Texas at Austin
</description>
    <link>http://tumrod.github.io/blog-cs371p/blog-cs371p/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://tumrod.github.io/blog-cs371p/blog-cs371p/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 01:02:50 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2016 01:02:50 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v2.5.3</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Week1: Let OOP begins</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hello World,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week was the first week of my last semester at UT. I had Professor Downing for my Software Engineering class last year. I really like the way he teaches. I learned a lot of things in that class, like different tools and technology. Therefore, I decided to take Object Oriented Programming with him this semester. In addition, in order to become a better software developer, I better get the foundation of programming: OOP down rigidly. Furthermore, learning C++ and different testing tools will enhance my coding qualities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;this-past-week&quot;&gt;This Past Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I had installed some of the tools on my laptop. Here are the tools: g++, gcov, gprof, doxygen, and Google Test. In my opinion, the development process is the same concept we learned in Software Engineering, for example, run harness and test harness, and unit test. The differences are the tools we used.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;obstacles&quot;&gt;Obstacles&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I attempted to install all of the tools on my laptop prior to the first day of class. I got most of the tools down on my mac with &lt;code&gt;brew&lt;/code&gt;. However, I am still struggling with gprof. I searched up online. It seems like &lt;code&gt;Instruments&lt;/code&gt; is the tool to use for profiling C++ on mac. I am still looking around for a better answer. If I cannot get all of the tools installed, I will just have to ssh into the CS machine since all of the requirement tools are already installed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;plan-for-next-week&quot;&gt;Plan for Next Week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My plan for next week would be working on Collatz project. Then, update my resume/portfolio website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tip-of-the-week&quot;&gt;tip-of-the-week&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I found an interesting YouTube video about C++ tip and I think sharing with y’all might be helpful. 
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Vy3DvF8nibA&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://img.youtube.com/vi/Vy3DvF8nibA/0.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;IMAGE ALT TEXT HERE&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;P.S. The rubber ducky method is actually what I did too and it actually works! By asking questions and talking through the code out loud make me realized where my mistake is.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 04:37:16 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://tumrod.github.io/blog-cs371p/blog-cs371p/posts/2016/01/24/week-1.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://tumrod.github.io/blog-cs371p/blog-cs371p/posts/2016/01/24/week-1.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>posts</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
